

#### **Details**

LOCATION

📍 Cluj-Napoca, Romania

+40 754 921 191

✓ vlad.blaj@bitladssoftware.com

NATIONALITY

Romanian

#### Links

Linkedin

Github

**Bitlads Software** 

#### Skills

React	4+ years
Java	5+ years
Typescript	1 year
Spring	5 years
React Native	2 years
Python	1 year
AWS	1+ years
Languages	
English	15+ years

#### **Courses**

German

Pega - Pega Certified System Architect (CSA)

3 vears

Scrum Alliance - Scrum Alliance Certified Scrum Master

# Vlad Blaj

Senior Full Stack Developer • Freelancer • Contractor • Founder of Bitlads Software

## **About me**

I am a Full Stack Developer with **6+ years of experience** eager to put in practice all the newest technologies, only interested in remote work. I have excellent planning skills, an effective time management system with which I am able to meet required deadlines. Confident in myself but always open to new ideas and suggestions.

# **Employment History**

## Senior Full Stack Software Developer at Aera Technology

ROMANIA AUGUST 2019 — PRESENT

Aera is a Cognitive Operating System that connects you with your business and autonomously orchestrates your operations. It enables this by creating processes with a drag and drop system which transform to executable programs.

- Improved process throughput execution by 40% by creating a Scheduler capable of
  executing high amounts of tasks across multiple nodes spread across multiple time
  zones.
- Optimized processes execution time by an average of 60% by creating a Java Profiler capable of analyzing and gathering data about different Aera Client Processes.

**Skills:** Spring, React, Spring Boot, React, Typescript, Redux, Apache Cassandra, Kafka, Redis, Quartz, AWS, Microservices

#### Software Developer at .msg Systems

ROMANNIA JULY 2017 — AUGUST 2019

Designed and developed a Web and Mobile Application used by Hilti's sales staff before, during and after customer visits to identify potential agreements and contact Hilti customers to evaluate and redefine existing agreements.

 Increased KPIs target values by 30% by creating a KPI aggregator tool for different sales and prices.

**Skills:** Java 8, Spring Boot, React, Hana Cloud Platform, Apache Olingo, SAP HANA, Junit, Mockito, JIRA, Bamboo, Flyway, Swagger, Hibernate, Microservices

#### Software Developer at .msg Systems

ROMANIA - JULY 2014 — JULY 2017

The client needed a tool to view filter and process candidates for different hiring positions. Previously Excel sheets were used to aggregate and process candidates. I developed and optimized a React Application which can process large number of candidates.

 Increased the hiring speed process and the number of candidates which could be processed during a hiring period by 50%.

Skills: Java, Spring, Hibernate, React, Liferay, Selenium, MySql

# **Internships**

#### Neusoft EDC

ROMANIA JULY 2014 — AUGUST 2014

I created an android application to track and record different outdoor sports. This app would display useful running metrics like calories burned, pace, laps and fastest laps.

Skills: Java, Android 2.3 SDK

# **Personal Projects**

#### Samson iOS YouTube App, Cluj-Napoca

ROMANIA JANUARY 2021 - JULY 2021

I Developed a React Native App in which the user is able to create **custom YouTube Playlists**. All playback functionalities are available plus the ability to view videos on YouTube using a **picture-in-picture capabilities**.

Added previously inexistent functionalities like playing cropped videos.

Skills: React Native, Expo, Animated View, React Native Router Flux, Redux, Native Base

#### **Binance Trading Bot**

ROMANIA SEPTEMBER 2020 — JUNE 2021

I created Trading Bot capable of executing orders based on a given set of trading strategies. Created and used APIs to communicate with Binance Platform in both Python and Java.

- Created a 5% per week return automated trade strategy.
- Added backtest functionality on different trading strategies.

Skills: Python (Pandas, NumPy, TimeSeries and Matplot lib)

#### **Education**

#### Masters Degree, Babes Bolyai University

ROMANIA, CLUJ-NAPOCA, OCTOBER 2015 — JULY 2017

Thesis: Improved "Detecting Energy Leak Bugs in Android Applications"

Optimized and increased the static analysis speed by more than 40%.

Skills: Java, ANTLR, MySql

#### **Bachelor Degree, Babes Bolyai University**

ROMANIA CLUJ-NAPOCA, OCTOBER 2021 — JULY 2015

Thesis: Detecting Energy Leak Bugs in Android Applications.

I developed a program using Java 8 which will detect and signal the presence of no-sleep-energy-bugs (battery drain bugs). It is a static analysis of the source code of an android project.

• Reduced battery usage for different Android Applications by more than 15%.

Skills: ANTLR 4.5, IntelliJ Plugin Development API, Java